Bosun Adepoju

Summary

An ambitious and analytical individual with experience in software development and data analysis spanning multiple industries. An experienced team player with a passion for problem-solving and applying acquired skills towards the solution of such problems.

Skills

Languages	C#, JavaScript, HTML5/CSS, Java, Python, SQL, T-SQL
Frameworks	Java Spring, .NET 5, .NET Core, Angular, React, Flask, JQuery, Nodejs
Tools	GIT, JIRA, AWS, Azure, Docker, Vagrant, SSMS, Entity Framework,
Databases	MS SQL, MySQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, CouchDB
Competencies	OOP, Unit Testing, Data Management, Algorithms & Data Structures, Backend & Frontend Development, Web API, Information Security, Cloud Development, Design Patterns, CI/CD, Statistical Analysis

Experience

T-Mobile US, Atlanta GA

Software Engineer (June 2020 – Present)

Circuit Clinical, Buffalo NY

Software Engineer (September 2018 – June 2020)

- A core member of the team involved in the development of a patient-centric clinical trial platform.
- Facilitated the development of complex relational database entities and stored procedures for data processes supporting all projects in SQL Server and PostgreSQL databases.
- Primarily responsible for a frontend redesign of a clinical trial platform including the development of features and APIs using .NET framework among other tools
- Implemented an automatic fuzzy matching algorithm that increased data transformation efficiency to over 80%.
- Developed an optimized autocomplete algorithm that is used throughout the platform.
- Developed a publicly available rating widget that occasionally pulls information from a secure API living on the platform.
- Lead the iterative migration of project backend from .NET Framework to .NET Core.
- Designed and developed a Covid-19 response web application to help automate the recording of coronavirus tests for employees at different organizations.
- Developed a coronavirus research trial tracking web application to automate patient recruitment at research centers across the United States and Canada.

Avalonix Group Inc., Amherst, NY

Software Developer

(September 2017 - June 2018)

- Built, tested, and deployed on an internal cloud server, an application that manages customer data, product inventory, sales data, and automates product shipment processes.
- Integrated system with Magento, UPS, and PayPal APIs for customer/product, shipping, and sales management respectively.
- Created an interface with ActiveX to enable automatic printing of shipping labels by Zebra printer.

Open Learning Exchange, Cambridge, MA

Software Developer Intern (remote) (January 2018 – May 2018)

- Participated in the development of Docker cloud-based PLANET educational system.
- Supported both frontend and backend code development using Angularis and CouchDB respectively.
- Worked remotely and actively updated codebase for review while effectively communicating with designers and product managers.
- Assisted in the migration of the PLANET App from CouchDB to PouchDB NoSQL database system to support the PWA.

Appiculate, Lagos, Nigeria

Software Developer Intern (February 2015 – November 2015)

AWOOF Rewards App

Developed and managed a wallet socket system as a microservice for the Awoof Mobile Application. The microservice integrates with the rewards platform and manages wallet transactions.

Projects

RUNMED Hospital Management System - Redeemer's University

Role:

Development Lead

Tools:

• JavaScript, Nodejs, MongoDB, HTML/CSS, Java, ExpressJS, D3.js

Details:

 A web-based system hosted on an internal university network, which provides easy communication and data access for the school clinic. The system encompasses every area of the clinic which includes medical, financial, administrative, legal, and compliance. The system provides integrated solutions like data access/storage and communication for services involving the pharmacy, inpatient/outpatient management, billing, laboratory, appointment scheduling, and ward management.

Education

Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA

MSc. Computer Science, exp. 2022

D'Youville College, Buffalo, NY

BSc. Health Analytics, 2019

Redeemer's University, Osun, Nigeria BSc. Computer Science, 2015 (transfer)